So I have a programming assignment for you.
我为你准备了一个编程任务
I would like you to implement the C++ program for
我希望你为卡尔曼滤波器更新方程
the Kalman filter update equations.
编写一个 C++ 程序
Let me help you get started.
开始时我会帮你
So here is the starting code.
这里是初始代码
For matrix manipulation, I would like you to use the Eigen library,
为了进行矩阵运算 我必须包括头文件Eigen/Dense
it has no dependencies and it's really easy to use.
它没有依赖 非常易用
For more details about how to integrate the Eigen library,
要了解如何使用 Eigen 库
take a look at the documentation which I've linked to below.
你可以看看下面链接提供的文档
In order to perform matrix operations, I have to include the Eigen/Dense header.
为了进行矩阵运算 我必须包括 Eigen/Dense 头
Additionally, all classes and functions defined in
此外，头文件中定义的所有类和函数
this header are in the Eigen name space, so I use it here.
都在 Engen 命名空间里 所以我在这里使用了改命名空间
Next, I'm going to show you some examples of working with matrices and
下面 我来通过几个例子展示 main
vectors in the main function.
函数中的矩阵和向量操作
You'll be able to run this examples in the code editor after this video.
你可以在本视频的代码编辑器中运行这些例子
You can create a vertical vector of two elements with a common like this.
你可以使用逗号分割，来创建一个包括两个分量的垂直向量
And if the vector size was previously specified, you can use
如果向量大小之前指定过 你可以使用
the so-called comma initializer to set all the coefficients to some values.
comma initializer 设置所有系数的值
And you can use the cout comment to print out the vector,
你可以使用 cout 来打印出向量
as you will see here.
就像你在这里看到的一样
The matrices can be created in the same way.
矩阵创建方式相同
For example, this is an initialization
例如 这是一个初始的
of a (2,2) matrix with the values 1, 2, 3, and 4.
(2,2) 矩阵 值包括1、2、3 和 4
I print it here, and this is my output.
我在这里把它们打印出来 这是我的输出
You can use the same comma initializer, or
你同样可以使用 comma initializer
you can set each matrix value explicitly, like this.
或者 你也可以明确设置每个矩阵值 像这样
Also you can compute the transpose of a matrix with the transpose method.
你还可以使用 transpose 方法来计算一个矩阵的转置
And here is how you can get the matrix inverse.
这里是如何求逆矩阵
And you can multiply matrices and vectors,
你可以把矩阵和向量相乘
as you do with normal variables, as you can see here.
就像常规变量操作一样 请看这里
Now, that you've seen how to use the Eigen library,
现在 你已经知道了如何使用 Eigen 库
let's take a look at the code that you'll be working with in this quiz.
我们看看这次测验中你用到的代码
At the top of 'tracking_1D.cpp', I declared all the Kalman filter variables here.
在 track_1D.cpp 文件顶部 我声明了所有卡尔曼滤波器的变量
Jumping down into the main function, for our 1D motion case,
下面我们看一维运动案例的 main 函数
I initialize them with the same values as in the previous lesson.
使用前一课同样的值初始化
You can't see them all right now, but I promise they are there.
现在还无法全部看到它们 我向你保证 它们都在这里
And here is my mostly empty filter function, where I iterate
这里是一个几乎全空的滤波器函数 我遍历了
over my list of measurements and where I want you to add your code.
所有的测量值 希望你能在这里添加你的代码
Concretely, I want you to implement the measurement update and the prediction
具体来说 我希望你进行测量值更新 并在循环内
steps inside the loop, given all the matrices initialized before.
完成预测步骤 依据是所有之前初始化过的矩阵
If you need some help, take a look back at the filter implementation you made
如果你需要帮助 可以回顾一下你在 Sebastian 的课上
in Sebastian's lesson.
学习的滤波器实现
After this video, you can find the link to the same programming quiz in Python.
在本视频后 有一个链接 点击即可打开使用 Python 完成的同一个编程测试
Good luck.
祝你好运！